principles.com 2019-04-05

# Principles by Ray Dalio - PRIOS, LLC PRIVACY POLICY

This Privacy Policy will go into effect on . 

This Privacy Policy explains how Principles, LLC and PRIOS, LLC, formerly known as Management Principles, LLC, (collectively, “ _ **PRIOS**_ ,” “ _ **we**_ ” or “ _ **us**_ ”) collect, use, disclose and retain information about you when you access or use our websites, mobile applications and other online products and services that link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, the “ _ **Services**_ ”), or otherwise interact with us.

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make changes, we will notify you by revising the date at the top of this policy and, in some cases, we may provide you with additional notice (such as adding a statement to our website homepage or sending you a notification). We encourage you to review our Privacy Policy whenever you access the Services or otherwise interact with us to stay informed about our information practices and the choices available to you.

## CONTENTS

Collection of Information  
Use of Information  
Sharing of Information  
Data Retention  
Social Sharing Features  
Advertising and Analytics Services Provided by Others  
Transfer of Information to the U.S. and Other Countries  
Your Choices  
Individuals in the European Economic Area (“EEA”)  
Contact Us  

## COLLECTION OF INFORMATION

#### Information We Collect from You

When you create an account, we ask you to provide your first name, last name, and email address, and we ask you to create a password. You also may be prompted to provide a profile photo when using some of our Services. We also collect information about your occupation and employer and other information you choose to share when you submit comments through the Services, fill out a form, participate in a contest or promotion, communicate with us via third party social media sites, request customer support, or otherwise communicate with us.

We also collect information about your use of the Services, such as: the search strings you enter; situations you suggest or tag as favorites; principles you create, edit, save or tag as favorites; ratings you assign to principles and other content; case study ratings and answers you provide; content you bookmark; media you view or interact with in our Services; and other preferences you express or content you provide when using the Services.

When you access or use our Services, we automatically collect information about you, including:

  * **Log Information:** We collect information related to your access to and use of the Services, including the type of browser you use, app version, access dates and times, pages viewed, your IP address, the country from which you access our Services, and the page you visited before navigating to our Services.
  * **Device Information:** We collect information about the computer or mobile device you use to access our Services, including the hardware model, operating system and version, unique device identifiers, and mobile network information.
  * **Information Collected by Cookies and Similar Tracking Technologies:** We (and our service providers) use different technologies to collect information, including cookies and web beacons. Cookies are small data files stored on your hard drive or in device memory that help us run analytics to improve our Services and your experience, track your preferences, see which areas and features of our Services are popular, and count visits. Web beacons (also known as “pixel tags” or “clear GIFs”) are electronic images that may be used in our Services or emails and help deliver cookies, count visits, and understand usage and campaign effectiveness. For more information about cookies and how to disable them, see Your Choices below.

#### Information We Collect from Others

We may also obtain information about you from other sources. For example, if you create or log into your account through a social media site, we will have access to certain information from that site, such as your name, email address, profile photo, other account or profile information, and friends lists, in accordance with the authorization procedures determined by such social media site.

## USE OF INFORMATION

We use the information we collect for various purposes, including to:

  * Provide, maintain and improve our Services, including to provide you with more relevant and personalized content;
  * Identify and authenticate users and send technical notices, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages;
  * Respond to your comments and questions and provide customer service;
  * Communicate with you about products, services, and events offered by PRIOS and our partners, and provide news and information we think will be of interest to you (see Your Choices below for information about how to opt out of these communications at any time);
  * Monitor and analyze trends, usage, and activities in connection with our Services;
  * Detect and prevent illegal or objectionable activities and protect the rights and property of PRIOS and others;
  * Personalize your online experience and the advertisements you see when you use the Services or third-party platforms based on your preferences, interests, and browsing behavior;
  * Facilitate contests, sweepstakes, and promotions and process and deliver entries and rewards; and
  * Carry out any other purpose described to you at the time the information was collected.

## SHARING OF INFORMATION

We will not share personal information about you, except in the following circumstances:

  * With vendors, service providers, and consultants that need access to such information to perform services for us, including to help us store information, authenticate users, send transactional and promotional communications, and debug, secure and improve our Services;
  * In response to a request for information if we believe disclosure is in accordance with, or required by, any applicable law or legal process, including lawful requests by public authorities to meet national security or law enforcement requirements;
  * If we believe your actions are inconsistent with our user agreements or policies, if we believe you have violated the law, or to protect the rights, property, and safety of PRIOS or others;
  * In connection with, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of company assets, financing or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by another company;
  * Between and among PRIOS and our current and future parents, affiliates, subsidiaries, and other companies under common control and ownership;
  * If you participate in the interactive areas of our Services, certain information about you may be displayed publicly on our Services and on third-party sites, such as your photos, videos, comments, ratings, principles, posts, and other information you choose to provide; and
  * With your consent or at your direction.

In certain instances, we may also share aggregated or de-identified information that cannot reasonably be used by those third parties to identify you.

## DATA RETENTION

We store the information we collect about you for as long as is necessary for the purpose(s) for which we originally collected it, or for other legitimate business purposes, including to meet our legal, regulatory, or other compliance obligations. Please refer to Your Choices below for information about how to deactivate your account and other choices available to you.

The Services may offer social sharing features and other integrated tools, such as links to share information about PRIOS on social media sites. Your use of such features enables the sharing of information with your friends or the public, depending on the settings you establish with the entity that provides the social sharing feature. For more information about the purpose and scope of data collection and processing in connection with social sharing features, please visit the privacy policies of the entities that provide these features.

## ADVERTISING AND ANALYTICS SERVICES PROVIDED BY OTHERS

We may allow others to provide analytics services and serve advertisements on our behalf across the web and in mobile applications. These entities may use cookies, web beacons, device identifiers and other technologies to collect information about your use of the Services and other websites and applications, including your IP address, web browser, mobile network information, pages viewed, time spent on pages or in apps, links clicked, and conversion information. This information may be used by PRIOS and others to, among other things, analyze and track data, determine the popularity of certain content, deliver advertising and content targeted to your interests on our Services and other websites and mobile applications, and better understand your activity. For more information, please see our Cookie Policy. In addition, to learn more about interest-based ads, or to opt out of having your web browsing information used for behavioral advertising purposes, please visit <http://www.aboutads.info/choices>. For individuals in the EEA, please visit <https://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>. Your device may also include a feature (“Limit Ad Tracking” on iOS or “Opt Out of Interest-Based Ads” or “Opt Out of Ads Personalization” on Android) that allows you to opt out of having certain information collected through apps used for behavioral advertising purposes.

## TRANSFER OF INFORMATION TO THE U.S. AND OTHER COUNTRIES

PRIOS is based in the United States and we process and store information in the U.S. and other countries. Therefore, we and our service providers may transfer your information to, or store or access it in, jurisdictions that may not provide equivalent levels of data protection as your home jurisdiction. We will take steps to ensure that your personal data receives an adequate level of protection in the jurisdictions in which we process it.

## YOUR CHOICES

#### Account Information

You may update certain account information you provide to us at any time by logging into your account and adjusting your settings. If you no longer want us to process information about you, you can request that we deactivate your account through the customer support functions of our Services, but note that we may retain certain information as required by law or for legitimate business purposes. We may also retain cached or archived copies of information about you for a certain period of time.

#### Cookies

Most web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove or reject browser cookies. Please note that if you choose to remove or reject cookies, this could affect the availability and functionality of our Services.

#### Promotional Communications

You may opt out of receiving promotional emails from PRIOS by following the instructions in those emails. If you opt out, we may still send you non-promotional emails, such as those about your account or updates to our user terms or policies.

#### Mobile Push Notifications/Alerts

With your consent, we may send promotional and non-promotional push notifications or alerts to your mobile device. You can deactivate these messages at any time by changing the notification settings on your mobile device.

## INDIVIDUALS IN THE EUROPEAN ECONOMIC AREA (EEA)

If you are in the EEA, you have certain rights and protections under the law regarding the processing of your personal data.

#### Legal Basis for Processing

If you are in the EEA, when we process your personal data we will only do so in the following situations:

  * We need to use your personal data to perform our responsibilities under our contract with you (e.g., providing the services you have requested).

  * We have a legitimate interest in processing your personal data. For example, we may process your personal data to send you marketing communications, to communicate with you about changes to our Services, and to secure and improve our Services.

  * We find such processing is necessary to comply with our legal obligations.

  * We have your consent to do so. When your consent is the legal basis for our processing, you may withdraw such consent at any time.

#### Data Subject Requests

If you are in the EEA, you have the right to access personal data we hold about you and to ask that your personal data be corrected, erased, or transferred. You may also have the right to object to, or request that we restrict, certain processing. If you would like to exercise any of these rights, you may contact us as indicated below. If you have created an account to access and use our Services, you may also update certain personal data by logging into your account.

#### Questions or Complaints

If you are in the EEA and have a concern about how we process personal data that we are not able to resolve, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the data privacy authority where you reside. For contact details of your local Data Protection Authority, please see: <https://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm>.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at: [legal@principles.com](mailto:legal@principles.com) or  
PRIOS, LLC  
Attn: Legal  
One Glendinning Place  
Westport, Connecticut 06880
